Guide to the C. D. Wright Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- October 2012 Acquisition, 1923-2012; 18.63; (24 boxes)
  - Princeton 2006 (Box 39)
  - Retablos, 1999-1998, undated (Box 39)
  - Reviews of C.D. Wright's work Deepstep Come Shining & Steal Away, 1998-2005 (Box 39)
  - Rhode Island Council for the Humanities, 2005 (Box 39)
  - Rising, Falling, Hovering, 2005-2007 (Box 40)
  - Senior Search 2011, 2010-2011; 2 (Box 40)
  - Sharma Prageeta Roan Jatte nomination by CD Wright, undated (Box 40)
  - UT Austin 08 2007 (Box 40)
  - Willis promotion review, 2010 October (Box 40)
  - "Because we have been here..." Daedalus proofs Sp 08, 2008 (Box 40)
  - Writers on writing, 2005-2008, undated (Box 40)
  - Xue Di 2001, 1998-2001 (Box 40)
  - Zunita, Raoul, 2009, undated (Box 40)
  - Additional matter, 1999-2002 (Box 40)
    Includes 6 computer disks
    2012-ycal-82-0017: May 65-Nov 65, TDH
    2012-ycal-82-0018: feb-Sep 69
    2012-ycal-82-0019: Sept 69-Mar 70
    2012-ycal-82-0020: untitled V's photos
    2012-ycal-82-0021: Swimming Pool, Forrest City, April 1935
  - Ark Council of Human Relat. U of A., 1962-2006, undated (Box 40)
  - Beifuss, undated (Box 40)
  - Book notes, 2006-2012, undated (Box 40)
  - Nov 07 draft (Box 40)
  - Ellis, 1977-2007 (Box 40)
  - Forrest city trips (two), 2005, undated (Box 40)
  - Harrison/Cleansing reconciliation, 2003-2004, undated (Box 40)
  - Harvell, Shirley F.C. 2002 program, 2005-2009, undated (Box 40)
  - Integration, voting, school, etc. now, 2004-2007, undated (Box 40)
  - Interim notes, 2004-2006, undated (Box 40)
  - Interim L. V. Harwell 2002, 2002, undated (Box 40)
  - King, 2005, undated (Box 40)
  - KY friends + cousins, 2005-2006, undated (Box 40)
  - Many Voices FC 1970-1972, 1970-1972, undated (Box 40)
  - McDaniel, Freddie, 2005-2006 (Box 40)
  - Memphis, 2003-2006, undated (Box 40)
  - Misc. images, undated (Box 40)
  - FU misc., 1969-2007 (Box 40)
  - Notables east ark delta, undated (Box 40)
  - Story matkin-Rawn + Wisconsin archives, 2006, undated (Box 40)
  - Times Herald Gazette, ANC Council on Human Relations, etc., 1965-2006, undated (Box 40)
  - Harwell scrapbook Times Herald 69, 1969, undated (Box 40)
  - Timeline matter, 1969-2002, undated (Box 40)
  - Vittitow, MaryPat, undated (Box 40)
  - V the inimitable, 1959-2006 (Box 41)
  - Vittitow materials for One with Others, 1965-1969, undated; 2 (Box 41)
  - Halvard Johnson, 2002 April 17 (Box 41)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 41)
  - Photos, undated (Box 41)
  - Notebook, undated (Box 41)
  - One Big Self, undated (Box 41)
  - Border notes, undated (Box 41)
  - Tooth for Homicides D. Luster, undated (Box 41)
  - Travels and projects with D. Luster (Box 41)
  - Notebooks, undated; 2 (Box 41)
  - Cooling Time, undated (Box 41)
  - Deepstep Come Shining (Box 41)
  - Octopus 40 watts, 2008, undated (Box 41)
  - One with Others draft, undated; 4 (Box 41)
  - One with Others, draft, undated; 4 (Box 42)
  - Blue Duck, draft, undated (Box 42)
  - A Farm Boy's story, draft, 2006, undated (Box 42)
  - Cooling Time, 2001, undated (Box 42)
  - Copper Canyon correspondences, 2004-2005 (Box 42)
  - Robert Creeley emails, 2004-2005 (Box 42)
  - Draft Like Something Flying Backward, undated; 2 (Box 42)
  - Like Something Flying Backward typescript (early), Bloodaxe 06, undated; 2 (Box 42)
  - Mary Jo Bang ms elegy, 2006, undated (Box 43)
  - One Big Self copy edits, 2006 (Box 43)
  - Current One Big Self Jan '06, 2005-2006, undated (Box 43)
  - Big Self forward cc edition drafts, undated (Box 43)
  - Parnassus, 2005, undated (Box 43)
  - Ploughshares, 2002 (Box 43)
  - Rising Falling Hovering, manuscript CD Wright 2008 Copper Canyon Press (Box 43)
  - Rising Falling Hovering, draft, undated (Box 43)
  - Rising Falling Hovering, final proofs (Box 43)
  - Rising Falling Hovering, proofs, 2007, undated; 2 (Box 43)
  - Current solicitations, 1997-2005, undated (Box 43)
  - Steal Away, mss, undated (Box 43)
  - MS Taggart (rec to wiegers), 2006-2007 (Box 43)
  - Letters, 1985-2011, undated; 2 (Box 43)
  - Cassette, 1995 June 15 (Box 43)
  - A Transcendental Almanac (Box 43)
  - American Poet: The Journal of The Academy of American Poets Fall 2010 (Box 43)
  - Arkansas Life, 2011 March (Box 44)
  - Bloodaxe Books, complete list, 2006-2007 (Box 44)
  - Bookforum, 2007 December
  - The Washington Post, Book World, 2006 October
  - Boston Review, 2006
  - 238th opening convocation, 2001 September 4 (Box 44)
  - Professorships at Brown University, 2005 (Box 44)
  - Brown University the Two Hundred and Thirty-Third Commencement, 2001 (Box 44)
  - The Bunting Institute of Radcliffe College Society of Institute Fellows, undated (Box 44)
  - In/Vision, 2005 (Box 44)
  - Language Change; Poetry, Politics, and Common Usage, 2001 (Box 44)
  - Hebrew language publications, 2008
  - Lila Wallace-Reader's Digest Writers' Awards, 1997 (Box 44)
  - 30th annual Twentieth-Century Literature Conference 2002, 2002 February (Box 44)
  - Marginalia, The Magazine of the Piper Center for Creative Writing, College of Liberal Arts and Sciences, 2008 (Box 44)
  - The New Yorker, 2011 January 3 (Box 44)
  - 2002 Pew Fellowships in the Arts (Box 44)
  - The 12th Biennial Geraldine R. Dodge Poetry Festival, 2008 September (Box 44)
  - Poets & Writers magazine, 2008 (Box 44)
  - Fine Arts Work Center in Provincetown, 2002-2003; 2 (Box 44)
  - Poetry Society of America, 2002 May 2 (Box 44)
  - Cross Roads; Journal of the Poetry Society of America, 1999-2003; 2 (Box 44)
  - The Oxford American, Winter Reading Issue, 2006 (Box 44)
  - Community of Writers, 2004-2006 (Box 44)
  - Vermont Studio Center, 2005 (Box 44)
  - Writing America, undated (Box 44)
  - America Here & Now (Eric Fischl), 2008-2011 (Box 44)
  - E. E. Wright funeral prep, 2009, undated (Box 44)
  - Hong Kong Poetry Festival, 2011 (Box 44)
  - Johnson, J. Chester, 2010-2011 (Box 44)
  - Palm Beach Poetry Festival, 2010-2011 (Box 44)
  - Ronk, Martha, undated (Box 44)
  - Jean Valentine + other drafts, 2011 (Box 44)
  - VII Granada International Poetry Festival, 2011 February (Box 44)
  - WCW, 1923-2011, undated (Box 44)
  - Writings CD Wright 2011, 2011, undated (Box 44)
  - Drafts '05, undated (Box 44)
  - Notebooks, 2009, undated; 3 (Box 45)
  - Selection for Bloodaxe PGST, R,F,H post selected, 2010, undated (Box 45)
  - Obscurity and Legacy, through drafts, 2011, undated (Box 45)
  - Kaminsky and Valentine; Tsvetaeva, undated (Box 45)
  - Vivek ms, 2012, undated (Box 45)
  - Notes, poems, undated (Box 45)
  - FG, 1983-2007, undated (Box 45)
  - Cal Bedient ms, undated (Box 45)
  - Intros + blurbs, undated (Box 45)
  - Programs, 2011-2012 (Box 45)
  - Events 2011 2012, 2010-2012 (Box 45)
  - Earlier programs 2001; catalogues 2003, 2001-2003; 2 (Box 45)
  - Various correspondence, 2010-2012 (Box 45)
  - C. D. Wright invue, (1 cassette tape) (Box 45)
  - Computer files, (81 disks) (Box 45)
    Computer disks are restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    2012-ycal-82-0022: CD interview revised...
    2012-ycal-82-0023: [acomp?]99, 4-6-00...
    2012-ycal-82-0024: recs, nominations, etc., 98/99-
    2012-ycal-82-0025: business 2000...
    2012-ycal-82-0026: Arschilo 4 Girl Friend poems...
    2012-ycal-82-0027: Blue Duck, 5-2-{99?]...
    2012-ycal-82-0028: 12-17-95, 11-2-97, girl friend poems
    2012-ycal-82-0029: blue duck (2000)
    2012-ycal-82-0030: of the mulberry family
    2012-ycal-82-0031: FTE strategy...
    2012-ycal-82-0032: Harkes tribute, playwriting and/college letter
    2012-ycal-82-0033: coolingtime (continued), 27 July 98
    2012-ycal-82-0034: Unlabelled
    2012-ycal-82-0035: honors, Allison
    2012-ycal-82-0036: 98-99 [?], jr. fiction, cv. 4-6-2000...
    2012-ycal-82-0037: 69 hidebond, eroc syllabus
    2012-ycal-82-0038: Prose, Wages of Poetry...
    2012-ycal-82-0039: cv\bio 11-5-97, update 2-28-98...
    2012-ycal-82-0040: Creative Writing Self Study...
    2012-ycal-82-0041: St. Joseph's, Foley/strategy...
    2012-ycal-82-0042: Deepstep, 11-10-95...
    2012-ycal-82-0043: Deepstep for CD, 1-11-98
    2012-ycal-82-0044: cool/deep, pomes.mim?
    2012-ycal-82-0045: Deepstep 11-6-96...
    2012-ycal-82-0046: Unlabelled
    2012-ycal-82-0047: Unlabelled
    2012-ycal-82-0048: Unlabelled
    2012-ycal-82-0049: Alias
    2012-ycal-82-0050: Tooth Eye I
    2012-ycal-82-0051: B pics argentina + childhood
    2012-ycal-82-0052: argentina, arkansas...
    2012-ycal-82-0053: Deb + Kevin wedding, 4/19/08...
    2012-ycal-82-0054: Mom 1
    2012-ycal-82-0055: Mom 1 (copy) variant (better)
    2012-ycal-82-0056: AE Wright, DVD Dec 09, made by FG
    2012-ycal-82-0057: 2 photos, mom + dad
    2012-ycal-82-0058: c, b, f photos
    2012-ycal-82-0059: 12-18-05 all on desktop, CD
    2012-ycal-82-0060: bloodaxee pdfs + desktop, 12-3-06
    2012-ycal-82-0061: a few files to cover in case of loss in transfer, 11-22-06
    2012-ycal-82-0062: V docs, Feb 07
    2012-ycal-82-0063: emails, 07-08, G-J
    2012-ycal-82-0064: lame duck emails 06, 07, 08
    2012-ycal-82-0065: P-R emails, 07-08
    2012-ycal-82-0066: L'd email, 07-08
    2012-ycal-82-0067: older matter misc, 2-07
    2012-ycal-82-0068: docs [?] pdf, ipg, old matter palm odd
    2012-ycal-82-0069: lit arts 07...
    2012-ycal-82-0070: Argentina England 08 email...
    2012-ycal-82-0071: Yale, Brian, Humanities...
    2012-ycal-82-0072: Contacts, 08-09
    2012-ycal-82-0073: email, students '09
    2012-ycal-82-0074: mail, 2009, friends...
    2012-ycal-82-0075: photos, palm odd
    2012-ycal-82-0076: Poetry everywhere
    2012-ycal-82-0077: The United States of Poetry
    2012-ycal-82-0078: The United States of Poetry
    2012-ycal-82-0079: students 10...
    2012-ycal-82-0080: Brecht, 09-10, Luster, 09-10...
    2012-ycal-82-0081: misc. Italy...
    2012-ycal-82-0082: bloodaxe 09-10...
    2012-ycal-82-0083: sent items 09-10
    2012-ycal-82-0084: Beinecke Rare Book & Manuscript Library YCAL Reading Series...
    2012-ycal-82-0085: Feb 08 (laptop)...
    2012-ycal-82-0086: Entourage 08 Feb, AWP, NYC
    2012-ycal-82-0087: [?] feb 08, AFMO (anthology is not for mothers only)...
    2012-ycal-82-0088: b notes blue flower, feb 09
    2012-ycal-82-0089: sent email 07, spg 08, fall 09
    2012-ycal-82-0090: sept 07 file 1...
    2012-ycal-82-0091: Sept 07 disk 2
    2012-ycal-82-0092: brown spg 09, lerner 09-10...
    2012-ycal-82-0093: cop canyon; writing matters, 09-10
    2012-ycal-82-0094: C.D. Wright reading from her work for the University of Arizona...
    2012-ycal-82-0095: C.D. Wright #1, 7/16/1999...
    2012-ycal-82-0096: C.D. Wright #2, 7/16/1999...
    2012-ycal-82-0097: One Big Self...
    2012-ycal-82-0098: Poem Present, Readings & Lectures 2005-2006
    2012-ycal-82-0099: The Poetry Programme, CD Wright, 28.07.07...
    2012-ycal-82-0100: 1PNHK 2011
    2012-ycal-82-0101: Poet CD Wright Weaves History, Reporting...
    2012-ycal-82-0102: Richard Price--CD Wright, October 20, 2010
  - Adamo, 1997, undated (Box 45)
  - Ali, undated (Box 45)
  - Berger, undated (Box 45)
  - Star Block, 2002, undated (Box 45)
  - Briante, undated (Box 45)
  - Burt, undated (Box 45)
  - Cole, Peter, undated; 2 (Box 45)
  - Crawford, 1998, undated (Box 46)
  - Dent, undated (Box 46)
  - Field, Thalia, undated; 2 (Box 46)
  - Forche, Blue Hour, undated (Box 46)
  - Forche, undated (Box 46)
  - Gilfillan, undated (Box 46)
  - High, J., undated (Box 46)
  - Hix, 1999, undated (Box 46)
  - Holman, Bob, undated (Box 46)
  - Junghans, 1999 (Box 46)
  - Lazer, H., 2000, undated (Box 46)
  - Kleindschmidt/Mayes, 1996, undated (Box 46)
  - Nelson, undated (Box 46)
  - Spalding, undated (Box 46)
  - Stein, 1994 (Box 46)
  - Taggart/Aeschylus fragments, undated (Box 46)
  - Tanning, undated (Box 46)
  - Waldrop, undated; 4 (Box 47)
  - Wellman, 2001 (Box 47)
  - Adamo, undated (Box 47)
  - Bracho, undated (Box 47)
  - Bogen, Don, undated (Box 47)
  - Brigham, Besmilr, 1969, 2000; 2 (Box 47)
  - Carruth, undated (Box 47)
  - Martin Earl, 2009, undated (Box 47)
  - Jarnot, 1992 (Box 47)
  - Lerner, 2003 May (Box 47)
  - Rodrigo Garcia Lopes Mar 14, 1995-2007, undated (Box 47)
  - Ray McDaniel rec 07, 2006-2007, undated (Box 47)
  - Nakayasa, 2002 May (Box 47)
  - Osman, undated (Box 47)
  - Saenz, undated (Box 47)
  - Schapira, undated (Box 47)
  - Shapiro, 1999 (Box 47)
  - Tietz, undated (Box 48)
  - Truitt, Sam, 2001-2007, undated; 2 (Box 48)
  - Tynes, Jen, 2005, undated (Box 48)
  - Waldrop, undated (Box 48)
  - Weinberger, undated (Box 48)
  - Welish, 2003, undated; 2 (Box 48)
  - Whitbeck, 2006 April (Box 48)
  - Xi Chuan ms, 2006-2007, undated (Box 48)
  - Xu, undated (Box 48)
  - Don Bogen, An Algebra, undated (Box 48)
  - Johnson, Kent, undated (Box 48)
  - Lerner, Ben hovd, undated (Box 48)
  - Loncar, Michael, undated (Box 48)
  - Mejer, Valerie, 2009, undated; 3 (Box 48)
  - Rain of the Future drafts, undated; 4 (Box 49)
  - Taggart, John, undated; 2 (Box 49)
  - Xi Chuan, undated (Box 49)
  - Zurita Forward/ms 09, undated (Box 49)
  - Bourbeau, Lisa poem + images, undated (Box 49)
  - Broadsides, undated (Box 49)
  - McKernan, John (and family), undated (Box 49)
  - Tender broadside, 1993 (Box 49)
  - Wright, C.D., 1992-2009 (Box 49)
  - Waldman, Anne (poems), Ducornet, Rikki (illustrations) "Calendar", undated (Box 49)
  - Mails (cards + postcards), 1990-2004, undated (Box 49)
  - Letter press, 1997-2004 (Box 49)
  - Mixed broadsides, 1990-2012, undated (Box 49)
  - Mixed images, 2005-2008, undated (Box 49)
  - Chapbooks - Fraser, Kathleen "This Phrasing Unreliable", 1993 November 2 (Box 49)
  - Chapbooks - Nelson, Cary "Modern Poems", undated (Box 49)
  - Chapbooks - Nelson, Carly The Westmore Lecture: Poetry Chorus, 1993 March 11 (Box 49)
  - Chapbooks - Shapiro, David Memorial to Jan Palach, undated (Box 49)
  - Oversize
    - Letter press, 1984-2009, undated; 4 (Box 50 (Oversize))
    - Posters, 1981-2012; 9 (Box 51 (Oversize))
    - Other (Box 52 (Oversize))
    - Posters, 1990-2009, undated; 8 (Box 52 (Oversize))
    - MacArthur 2004, 2004, undated (Box 53 (Oversize))
    - Pamir's Poetry Journey 2006, 2004-2007, undated (Box 53 (Oversize))
    - Completed 05, 06, 2005-2006, undated (Box 53 (Oversize))
    - Calendar/pr, 2004-2007, undated (Box 53 (Oversize))
    - 2004 completed, 2004, undated (Box 53 (Oversize))
    - PR related 2003 (Box 53 (Oversize))
    - PR related to file 1999-2002 (Box 53 (Oversize))
    - Miscellaneous publications, 1985-2007 (Box 53 (Oversize))
    - News/clippings, 2006-2007 (Box 53 (Oversize))
    - Reviews, 2007, undated (Box 53 (Oversize))
    - Cold Cases LC, 2003-2004 (Box 53 (Oversize))
    - Completed 07 events, readings, 2006-2007 (Box 53 (Oversize))
    - Creeley promotional, 2005, undated (Box 54 (Oversize))
    - PR events 2008, undated (Box 54 (Oversize))
    - Steal Away, reviews, 2001-2005 (Box 54 (Oversize))
    - Griffin Prize, 2009, undated (Box 54 (Oversize))
    - Mexico, 2003-2004 (Box 54 (Oversize))
    - Boston Review, reviews, 2008 (Box 54 (Oversize))
    - Broadsides, 2007, undated (Box 54 (Oversize))
    - Book Forum, 2007 (Box 54 (Oversize))
    - Boston Review, 2006 (Box 54 (Oversize))
    - The Washington Post Book World, 2006 October (Box 54 (Oversize))
    - Integration, voting, school, etc. now, 2005-2007, undated (Box 54 (Oversize))
    - Hebrew Language publications, 2008 (Box 54 (Oversize))
    - VII Granada International Poetry Festival, 2011 February (Box 54 (Oversize))
  - Restricted Fragile Material
    - Audiovisual material
      - Untitled, undated; (1 audio cassette) (Box 55)
      - CD Wright Invue, 1995 June 15; (1 mini cassette) (Box 55)
      - New Letters on the Air: Contemporary Writers on Radio, undated; (1 audio cassette) (Box 55)
    - Computer disks, (102 computer disks) (Box 56)
      2012-ycal-82-0001 - 2012-ycal-82-0102